let's assume you have bought some
jewelry and want to know whether it is
made of gold and is not fake how can
Physics help you with this first you
have to weigh the jewelry and determine
its massim then you have to find out the
volume v of the jewelry to do this you
use Archimedes principle this states
that the amount of water displaced is
exactly equal to the volume of the
immersed body so take a measuring cup of
water throw in the jewelry and look at
the milliliter scale to see how high the
water has
risen convert the value into cubic
met now the density row of the jewelry
material can be
calculated simply divide the mass by the
volume the gold has a density of
19,300 kg per cubic meter if you also
get this value then the jewelry is made
of real gold